<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>csv on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/csv/</link><description>Recent content in csv on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/csv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-10-nfl-4th-downs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-10-nfl-4th-downs/</guid><description>Introductory Setup This past Thanksgiving I headed over to Sioux City, IA to visit my folks, brother, sister-in-law, and baby sister. Thursday found my father and I watching the Chiefs game against the Cowboys (Dallas carried the day 31-28). At some point, my dad turned to me and said something to the effect of you, &amp;ldquo;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem like teams nowadays are going for it on fourth down far more than they used to?</description></item><item><title>WNBA Regular Season Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-07-06-wnba-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-07-06-wnba-blowouts/</guid><description>Given that we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work with the NBA and &amp;ldquo;blowouts&amp;rdquo; in a couple of different posts&amp;mdash;one here and another here&amp;mdash;I thought we might look at the WNBA too. So, first step, I found a Kaggle dataset that gave us data up until 2020, if I remember correctly. We then wrote some code to update to the most recent games:
import pandas as pd import numpy as np from nba_api.</description></item><item><title>NBA Regular Season Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</guid><description>So, spending some time looking at NBA blouwouts in the playoffs over time in previous posts, I wondered about blowouts in the regular season.
I found a dataset on Kaggle Datasets that had data from the very start of the NBA up until today.
So, we filtered out all the regular season games and then plotted the data. We have the raw blowout data in the first image and then the proportions in the second plot below:</description></item><item><title>As Promised---Skubal and Skenes Career K Projections</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</guid><description>As in my previous post I promised to look at both Skenes and Skubal and their projected trajectories towards 3000 career strikeouts. If we&amp;rsquo;re being honest, this benchmark is far from easy to achieve, only 19 pitchers in the history of baseball have done it before:
Pitcher Strikeouts Nolan Ryan 5,714 Randy Johnson 4,875 Roger Clemens 4,672 Steve Carlton 4,136 Bert Blyleven 3,701 Tom Seaver 3,640 Don Sutton 3,574 Gaylord Perry 3,534 Walter Johnson 3,509 Greg Maddux 3,371 Phil Niekro 3,342 Ferguson Jenkins 3,192 Pedro Martinez 3,154 Bob Gibson 3,117 Curt Schilling 3,116 CC Sabathia 3,093 John Smoltz 3,084 Justin Verlander 3,041 Max Scherzer 3,000 (IIRC, CC Sabathia and Justin Verlander are also on this list too.</description></item><item><title>More MLB Visualizations ... For a Larf</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</guid><description>With Tarik Skubal on the mound tomorrow&amp;mdash;Wednesday, June 18&amp;mdash;for the Tigers against Pittsburgh, considered by many to be the best pitcher in baseball, I thought we could take a look at Skubal&amp;rsquo;s projections real quick as a larf. I figured we could use the code from our previous blog post looking at Paul Skenes and Clayton Kershaw and see what we can see; just a couple changes to the player we&amp;rsquo;re looking at and we’re good to go:</description></item><item><title>Automating Syllabus Updating</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-syllabus-maker-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-syllabus-maker-stuff/</guid><description>In my previous post I mentioned off-handedly the task of updating the dates on my syllabi as I transition from the Fall to the Spring to the Summer semesters. I figured I would post some of the code to help out with this tiny little mini-project. (All the code for this is available in the following repository.)
I have a pretty simple Canvas main page that has all the dates, readings, and assignments laid out in a simple little table—all on one main page:</description></item></channel></rss>