<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>numpy on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/numpy/</link><description>Recent content in numpy on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/numpy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>As Promised---Skubal and Skenes Career K Projections</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</guid><description>As in my previous post I promised to look at both Skenes and Skubal. I was also thinking about my initial MLB post (where we were looking at Skenes and Kershaw). I can imagine a reader wondering how we determined what an &amp;ldquo;optimistic&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;pessimistic&amp;rdquo; trajectory for Skenes ultimately is &amp;hellip; I figured I would answer that in my writeup here of our Skenes vs. Skubal&amp;rsquo;s career K potential/trajectory. So let&amp;rsquo;s go producing a similar side-by-side comparison for these two but with the initial steps not being left out/omitted.</description></item><item><title>More MLB Visualizations ... For a Larf</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</guid><description>With Tarik Skubal on the mound tomorrow&amp;mdash;Wednesday, June 18&amp;mdash;for the Tigers against Pittsburgh, considered by many to be the best pitcher in baseball, I thought we could take a look at Skubal&amp;rsquo;s projections real quick as a larf. I figured we could use the code from our previous blog post looking at Paul Skenes and Clayton Kershaw and see what we can see; just a couple changes to the player we&amp;rsquo;re looking at and we’re good to go:</description></item><item><title>We've Done Some NBA and WNBA Data Analysis ... How About Some MLB?</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-15-skenes-vs-kershaw-career-strikeouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-15-skenes-vs-kershaw-career-strikeouts/</guid><description>Watching the LA Dodgers and SF Giants game yesterday&amp;mdash;Saturday, June 14, 2025&amp;mdash;the commentators were talking about Clayton Kershaw&amp;rsquo;s closing in a on 3000 career strikeouts. Having earlier watched Pittsburgh Pirates ace Paul Skenes go, I wonder if we could visualize the possibilities of the latter eventually clearing that line.
We can project Paul Skenes&amp;rsquo;s trajectory based on some estimates&amp;mdash;whether we&amp;rsquo;re really optimistic in certain K numbers per game or pessimistic&amp;mdash;and we get something like this:</description></item><item><title>WNBA Historical Stats</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-wnba-historical-stats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-wnba-historical-stats/</guid><description>Yay! The WNBA season is upon us and already started! Since I had recently done some analysis on the NBA Playoffs&amp;mdash;I figured I would goof around and play with the WNBA a little bit. In service of that, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
So, as always, we start with data gathering. I tried using the fabulous nba_api to grab data, but for years closer to the creation of the league (1997), things seemed a little spotty to me.</description></item><item><title>NBA Playoff Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-nba-playoff-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 13:01:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-nba-playoff-blowouts/</guid><description>Watching the 2025 NBA Playoffs has been a bit strange: huge blowouts (sometimes, often, unexpected) follow by razor-tight contests that go down to the very last possession or even into overtime.
After the Denver Nuggets&amp;rsquo; exit from the playoffs at the hands of the OKC Thunder, Aaron Gordon of the Nuggets has a rather intriguing post-game press conference where he himself mentioned the &amp;ldquo;blowouts&amp;rdquo; thing (thus making it not something just in my head, I suppose).</description></item></channel></rss>