<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work stuff on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/work-stuff/</link><description>Recent content in work stuff on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/work-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More _The Turn of the Screw_ Data Analysis</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</guid><description>I know I mentioned in an earlier post—a couple of different posts actually (here and here too)—that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of work with Henry James&amp;rsquo;s canonical The Turn of the Screw. I thought I would post a little bit more here of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to as of late with this. A student of mine was fascinated by the use of the words &amp;ldquo;prodigious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;portentous&amp;rdquo; in the Governess&amp;rsquo;s narrative in Turn.</description></item><item><title>Let's Do Some Real World HTML Table Parsing with Beautiful Soup</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</guid><description>Given that I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to chronicle my DH journeys here, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d showcase a little bit of my utilization of scraping data from a website with Beautiful Soup (docs are here).
Doing some research for a favorite student of mine, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wandering around websites devoted to law school. One website here has a really fantastic little table on the page that has everything one could want—especially if one is a little behind on deadlines and trying to catch up a bit (i.</description></item><item><title>Graduate-Level Course in Digital Rhetoric (Summer 2022)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course/</guid><description>After a few semesters of planning and learning, my Department is rolling out the sixth and final course in a slate of courses designed to get Illinois teachers ready and credentialed to teach dual-credit English composition courses in their high schools. This has been in partnership with my current institution&amp;rsquo;s College of Education, the &amp;ldquo;REAL Academy&amp;rdquo; and it has been quite a whirlwind road, lots of fun, lots of work, lots of opportunity for me to learn all kinds of new things.</description></item></channel></rss>