<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work stuff on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/work-stuff/</link><description>Recent content in work stuff on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/work-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visualizing Online Class Discussion Boards (redux)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</guid><description>In a very early post on this blog, I went through some of my incredibly kludgy attempts to visualize the discussion boards in my ENGL200: Introduction to Literature: Weird Fiction course that I have been teaching every semester since Fall of 2019. I have improved things quite a bit and made the worfklow a whole lot easier. I figured I could, once again, take everyone through the steps to see if it might be at all helpful for others with similar use-cases.</description></item><item><title>Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and you do a lot of teaching online (I know, I know, who among us don&amp;rsquo;t fit into that category today?) with courses that are really &amp;ldquo;Discussion Board&amp;rdquo;-heavy, you know that responding to students through Canvas&amp;rsquo;s LMS is, on its face, a bit of a bear. I have a tendency to produce some rather extensive comments to student posts each and every week. As Canvas veterans know all too well, there are all kinds of things about Canvas that are frighteningly &amp;ldquo;user-hostile,&amp;rdquo; as Robby Burns puts it.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Stylistic Tendencies Recent United States Supreme Court Justices (Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</guid><description>General Introduction (All of the code for this post is available in this repo here.)
Continuing off of the last two posts (here and here), I thought we might continue seeing what we could do with our Supreme Court Opinions dataset(s)—I was also fascinated and inspired by a nice little article on Wikipedia about the &amp;ldquo;Ideological leanings of United States Supreme Court justices,&amp;rdquo; which has some really nice images. I thought one might do a little exploratory work with the opinions of some of the more recently appointed Justices: in particular I wanted to look at the work done so far by Justices Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett; perhaps a little PCA work to see if we could work through any potential stylistic similarities between their opinions so far.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Utilizing the Top2Vec Library</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_20/</guid><description>Here in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue working on the same project used in the previous post (here) while trying out the Top2Vec library). As is so often the case, I came across this library via Dr. William Mattingly&amp;rsquo;s YoutTube channel, who devoted two different videos to using this library (here and here). So let&amp;rsquo;s jump in and see what we can do with this library.
This time around we&amp;rsquo;re using a slightly different dataset that comes Kaggle—it contains all of the USSC opinions from 1970 on.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Surrounding Abortion</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</guid><description>General Background (All code from this section is available in this repository here.)
Friday of last week, June 24th, 2022, was a profoundly dark day for a great many of us in the United States. Feeling somewhat helpless as the Supreme Court published the final draft of Dobbs v. Jackson Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Organization, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but fall back on old patterns. Not really knowing what else to do—I had a student with whom I had recently read the leaked original draft posted by Politico—I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but say to her when the opinion came down that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what else to do other than to get to reading.</description></item><item><title>Linear Regression in the Humanities(?!?!) ... not quite</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities_18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities_18/</guid><description>Working my way through some of the new lessons from Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;Data Scientist: Natural Language Processing Specialist&amp;rdquo; path, I was returning to some of the lessons on linear regression usage in machine learning contexts. I also happened across a really fantastic post from the &amp;ldquo;LaTeX Ninja&amp;rdquo; on &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning for the Humanities: A Very Short Introduction&amp;rdquo;—I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet come across this site yet and find it full of all kinds of fantastic little nuggets.</description></item><item><title>Fetching Data from a TOML File into a HUGO Table</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table_17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table_17/</guid><description>Continuing to learn the whole HUGO ecosystem here, I figured I would try a little testing of some things. What if I had a bunch of data in a simple .json or .toml or .yaml or whatever file and wanted to pull/fetch data from that file into one of my posts? I did have some data from the last post about Henry James&amp;rsquo;s use of certain words that we used to generate some of the graphs.</description></item><item><title>More _The Turn of the Screw_ Data Analysis</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis_16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis_16/</guid><description>I know I mentioned in an earlier post—and here—that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of work with Henry James&amp;rsquo;s canonical The Turn of the Screw. I thought I would post a little bit more here of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to as of late with this. A student of mine was fascinated by the use of the words &amp;ldquo;prodigious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;portentous&amp;rdquo; in the Governess&amp;rsquo;s narrative in Turn. She said she noticed it frequently.</description></item><item><title>Let's Do Some Real World HTML Table Parsing with Beautiful Soup</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing_15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing_15/</guid><description>Given that I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to chronicle my DH journeys here, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d showcase a little bit of my utilization of scraping data from a website with Beautiful Soup (docs are here).
Doing some research for a favorite student of mine, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wandering around websites devoted to law school. One website here has a really fantastic little table on the page that has everything one could want—especially if one is a little behind on deadlines and trying to catch up a bit (i.</description></item><item><title>Graduate-Level Course in Digital Rhetoric (Summer 2022)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course_14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course_14/</guid><description>After a few semesters of planning and learning, my Department is rolling out the sixth and final course in a slate of courses designed to get Illinois teachers ready and credentialed to teach dual-credit English composition courses in their high schools. This has been in partnership with my current institution&amp;rsquo;s College of Education, the &amp;ldquo;REAL Academy&amp;rdquo; and it has been quite a whirlwind road, lots of fun, lots of work, lots of opportunity for me to learn all kinds of new things.</description></item></channel></rss>