<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>digital humanities on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/digital-humanities/</link><description>Recent content in digital humanities on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/digital-humanities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More _The Turn of the Screw_ Data Analysis</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</guid><description>I know I mentioned in an earlier post—a couple of different posts actually (here and here too)—that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of work with Henry James&amp;rsquo;s canonical The Turn of the Screw. I thought I would post a little bit more here of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to as of late with this. A student of mine was fascinated by the use of the words &amp;ldquo;prodigious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;portentous&amp;rdquo; in the Governess&amp;rsquo;s narrative in Turn.</description></item><item><title>Let's Do Some Real World HTML Table Parsing with Beautiful Soup</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</guid><description>Given that I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to chronicle my DH journeys here, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d showcase a little bit of my utilization of scraping data from a website with Beautiful Soup (docs are here).
Doing some research for a favorite student of mine, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wandering around websites devoted to law school. One website here has a really fantastic little table on the page that has everything one could want—especially if one is a little behind on deadlines and trying to catch up a bit (i.</description></item><item><title>Graduate-Level Course in Digital Rhetoric (Summer 2022)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-23-grad-level-digital-rhetoric-course/</guid><description>After a few semesters of planning and learning, my Department is rolling out the sixth and final course in a slate of courses designed to get Illinois teachers ready and credentialed to teach dual-credit English composition courses in their high schools. This has been in partnership with my current institution&amp;rsquo;s College of Education, the &amp;ldquo;REAL Academy&amp;rdquo; and it has been quite a whirlwind road, lots of fun, lots of work, lots of opportunity for me to learn all kinds of new things.</description></item><item><title>Transforming TEI XML of _The Turn of the Screw_ into HTML</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-15-more-tots-hmtl-testing_introductory_post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-15-more-tots-hmtl-testing_introductory_post/</guid><description>All right, so let&amp;rsquo;s do a little bit of testing of the whole XML through XSLT process to get an HTML version of James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw with all my colored tags for it.
The original .xml and .xsl file are up and available in the GitHub repo.
And without further ado, here we go!</description></item><item><title>Text Encoding Initiative (TEI) Fun with Henry James's _The Turn of the Screw_</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james/</guid><description>My English Department colleague, Dr. Anna Ioanes, is teaching the standard course in &amp;ldquo;Critical Theory&amp;rdquo; this semester and students have been working their way through Henry James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw over the last few weeks. Somehow—not exactly sure how—I managed to forget how incredibly rich this text is and this is not even to mention the rich secondary criticism produced by this short little novella. Inspired—once again—by some posts from Jonathan Reeve over at Columbia (specifically, his nice write-up about sentence lengths in James along with his encoded .</description></item><item><title>Binary Text Classification Fun! ... with some Literary Texts by Willa Cather and Sarah Orne Jewett</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts/</guid><description>In my DH journey, the work of Dr. William Mattingly has been something of a constant companion and guide.
His video laying out the steps for a &amp;ldquo;Binary Data Classification&amp;rdquo; was clear and quite clarifying for me in all kinds of ways. The classifier&amp;rsquo;s job in this video was to see if it could tell the difference between the work of Oscar Wilde and Dan Brown. What if we tried a different pair of authors/texts?</description></item><item><title>Using Vector Space Models with Shakespeare's Plays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare/</guid><description>Much of the toe-dipping into this new DH field I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing as of late has centered around learning many of the kinds of projects carried out and then turning the methods within those projects onto mew artifacts. A while back I worked my way through Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont, and Allen Riddell&amp;rsquo;s Humanities Data Analysis: Case Studies with Python. I found a great deal of it thought-provoking and fascinating—especially the chapters devoted to modeling texts with vector spaces and the later chapter on stylometry, which focused on some texts by Hildegard of Bingen and Bernard of Clairvaux.</description></item><item><title>Viral Tweet Classification Project</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project/</guid><description>I had a bit of fun recently working on a machine learning classification project using some Twitter data (said project coming through Codecademy). The goal was to see if we could write some code to properly detect whether or not a tweet was viral (using the K-Nearest Neighbors algorithm). I also played around with a logistic regression model as well. All the code for the following is available in this repo.</description></item><item><title>Sentiment Analysis of Some Chicagoland Universities' Main Twitter Accounts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-02-15-twitter-sentiment-analysis_07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-02-15-twitter-sentiment-analysis_07/</guid><description>Well, February has come around and that&amp;rsquo;s the time at my school where we get all kinds of nice financial data about how wages and compensation by faculty rank compare between a number of &amp;ldquo;peer institutions&amp;rdquo; (the usual ones linked with USF here in Chicagoland are Benedictine, Dominican, Lewis, and Saint Xavier) I wondered a bit if one might do a little bit of data visualization not of financial information, but of, say, Twitter accounts.</description></item><item><title>Letting Excel Go and Departmental Assessment Reports</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 08:19:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</guid><description>For those that work in disciplines that are much closer to STEM fields than me over here in philosophy and literature, I have no doubt that most of what I want to showcase here will no doubt be the height of banality. As Department Chair, a good deal of the Assessment Reports each year fall to me. Historically, for the past couple of years I have been more than content to simply just keep all of the scores on our assessed outcomes in one gigantic Excel spreadsheet.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Plain Text and CSS Templates</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2021-12-27-playing-with-plain-text-and-css-templates_05/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2021-12-27-playing-with-plain-text-and-css-templates_05/</guid><description>Over the past few months I have been thinking a great deal about how to incorporate all this new knowledge about digital methodology, data science, data analytics, (scholarly and non-scholarly) work/writing in the &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo; era into the way I do things as a scholar, teacher, thinker, etc. One of the key people that has been really informative for me has been Jonathan Reeve over at Columbia University. One of his posts from earlier this year, &amp;ldquo;Rethinking the MLA Style Research Paper&amp;rdquo; was incredibly generative for me—and it nicely dovetailed with some work my Departmental colleagues have been doing on thinking about writing at our university (a project generously funded by the Arthur Vining Davis Foundation).</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Online Class Discussion Boards</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2019-12-31-visualizing-online-class-discussion-boards_04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2019-12-31-visualizing-online-class-discussion-boards_04/</guid><description>A Fantastic Anthology
So, this last semester I did another &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Literature&amp;rdquo; course (as I so often do)—this time around I decided to set the theme around that of &amp;ldquo;weird fiction.&amp;rdquo; Since the South Bend DHRI last May I have been thinking a great deal about this whole &amp;ldquo;data visualization&amp;rdquo; thing. I wanted to find some way to visually represent the stories in the anthology that students were gravitating to from week to week.</description></item><item><title>Still Playing Around with Python, NLTK, spaCy, etc.</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2019-12-24-still-playing-around-with-python-nltk-spacy-etc_03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 12:05:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2019-12-24-still-playing-around-with-python-nltk-spacy-etc_03/</guid><description>Ugh, so clearly my discipline in posting is nonexistent. It&amp;rsquo;s fine—I&amp;rsquo;m still just dipping my toes in the water here—and not only that, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in trying to document my learning curve here, such as it is &amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s a WordCloud for Bram Stoker&amp;rsquo;s Dracula:
This past July I got an opportunity to do a NEH Summer Seminar over at the University of Iowa (&amp;quot;Religion, Secularism, and the Novel&amp;quot;), where the group read a number of canonical novels (Crusoe, Silas Marner, Dracula, On the Road, and Home).</description></item></channel></rss>