<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data analysis on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/data-analysis/</link><description>Recent content in data analysis on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin vs. the DOW and NASDAQ</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-01-06-cryptos-vs-dow-jones-and-nasdaq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-01-06-cryptos-vs-dow-jones-and-nasdaq/</guid><description>So there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk lately about Microstrategy&amp;rsquo;s seemingly almost constant buys of Bitcoin almost every single day. There&amp;rsquo;s also been quite a lot of chatter recently about some other hardware companies, (Marvel Technologies, MARA, etc.) getting involved. We also have things like &amp;ldquo;Coinbase&amp;rdquo; that is frequently linked to Bitcoin as well.
I thought I would do some coding to see how correlated these stock tickers are with Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Building a Dash App to Visualize the 5, 13, 8 EMA Investment Strategy</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-14-building_a_dash_app_to_visualize_investment_strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-14-building_a_dash_app_to_visualize_investment_strategy/</guid><description>So, continuing to goof-around a little bit with applying my Python knowledge to analysis of the stock markets, I decided to build a Dash app with Plotly that would allow one to see real-time price action while also implementing the well-known &amp;ldquo;5-13-8 EMA&amp;rdquo; trading strategy.
It&amp;rsquo;s still a work-in-progress to be sure &amp;hellip; and it&amp;rsquo;s probably totally unnecessary&amp;mdash;such indicators and plots are quickly and easily used on platforms like Trading View and Ninja Trader, but I wondered if I could do myself, from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Economic Analyses: High-Yield Savings Accounts (HYSA) and Bitcoin ... Given Posible Reduction in the Interest Rate by the FED</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</guid><description>Okay, so recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving into using my Python knowledge to look at and analyze financial data. We know that the FED is next scheduled to meet on December 17-18 of this year. Many are predicting that we will see a decrease in interest rates.
So, if you have your money in a High-Yield Savings Account (HYSA)&amp;mdash;which you obviously should&amp;mdash;would it make more sense to move it elsewhere &amp;hellip; say, into Crypto?</description></item><item><title>Total *non sequitur*: Tracking the Price of Silver</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-30-tracking-silver-prices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-30-tracking-silver-prices/</guid><description>Silver Price Tracker So, my father has some vintage Silver pieces from 1973 and 1974 produced by the Franklin Mint with all kinds of different national banks on each one. We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to figure out how to unload them&amp;mdash;either to collectors or to folks that will simply melt them down for the silver alone. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a little coding.
The first is a plot over the last couple of months of Silver prices:</description></item><item><title>What Kind of Songs Do I Like? Goofing Around with the Spotify API and My Bizarre Music Tastes</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</guid><description>Some Introductory Remarks I was having a conversation with my most favorite student that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had in my entire career as a teacher a while back and we got to chatting about my little pattern of sending her songs I like from the &amp;ldquo;Discover Weekly&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Release Radar&amp;rdquo; playlists that come my way via Spotify. She and I seem to have very few similarities when it comes to music. She likes to say that I have somewhat &amp;ldquo;girlish&amp;rdquo; music tastes (not meant as a pejorative, far from it, at least, I think!</description></item></channel></rss>