<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>seaborn on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/seaborn/</link><description>Recent content in seaborn on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/seaborn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Kind of Songs Do I Like? Goofing Around with the Spotify API and My Bizarre Music Tastes</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</guid><description>Some Introductory Remarks I was having a conversation with my most favorite student that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had in my entire career as a teacher a while back and we got to chatting about my little pattern of sending her songs I like from the &amp;ldquo;Discover Weekly&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Release Radar&amp;rdquo; playlists that come my way via Spotify. She and I seem to have very few similarities when it comes to music. She likes to say that I have somewhat &amp;ldquo;girlish&amp;rdquo; music tastes (not meant as a pejorative, far from it, at least, I think!</description></item><item><title>Digital Rhetoric and Predictive Machine Learning Models on Twitter Data</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-measuring-twitter-engagement-and-digital-rhetoric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-measuring-twitter-engagement-and-digital-rhetoric/</guid><description>In my ENGE 515: Digital Rhetoric graduate-level course currently running (full list of courses is available through the USF REAL program, housed within the College of Education), we have been getting our feet wet in this field of rhetoric focused on the realm/world of &amp;ldquo;the digital&amp;rdquo; (I do notice too now—somehow it had slipped my mind—that I wrote a little bit already about how this course went last summer). This past week (Week 6), we had a read of some somewhat contemporary work in this field, namely:</description></item><item><title>Predictive Modeling with the 'OK Cupid' Dataset</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-machine-learning-with-ok-cupid-dataset/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-machine-learning-with-ok-cupid-dataset/</guid><description>The final project for Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Building a Machine Learning Model with Python&amp;rdquo; Skill Path asks students to do a little work with the &amp;ldquo;OK Cupid&amp;rdquo; dataset—the project is humorously, punningly titled: &amp;ldquo;Date-A-Scientist.&amp;rdquo; Students were tasked with trying to build some models to make predictions on this dataset. A Jupyter notebook with all the code and results follows here:</description></item><item><title>Hemingway (continued)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-fitzgerald-hemingway-continued/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-fitzgerald-hemingway-continued/</guid><description>In my last post, I shared some really simple text classification work on Hemingway, Fitzgerald, and Steinbeck. It was only after posting it that I noticed that Justin Rice beat me to the punch with his post &amp;ldquo;What Makes Hemingway Hemingway?&amp;rdquo; over on &amp;ldquo;The LitCharts Blog&amp;rdquo;. What was terribly curious to me was that Rice showcases some of the key characteristics that one thinks &amp;ldquo;makes Hemingway Hemingway&amp;rdquo;—sentence length, word length, lexical richness, dialogue proportion, parts of speech, characteristic words, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Fitzgerald ... Hemingway ... Steinbeck</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-07-fitzgerald-hemingway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-07-fitzgerald-hemingway/</guid><description>Lately I have been spending a fair amount of time working on my portfolio for the required &amp;ldquo;Post_Tenure Review&amp;rdquo; at my current institution. I spent quite a bit of time canvassing a great deal of the DH/computer programming learning I have acquired over the last couple of years. I gave a somewhat interesting test project version of some more stylometry/text classification work,1 focusing quite directly on some work another (former) student of mine, William Mastin, and I have been doing on one of his most favorite authors, Ernest Hemingway.</description></item></channel></rss>