<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>literary style on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/literary-style/</link><description>Recent content in literary style on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/literary-style/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTML Version of _The Turn of the Screw_ Testing</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-hj_tots_full_version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-hj_tots_full_version/</guid><description>The Turn of the Screw The Turn of the Screw By Henry James Encoded by: Dr. Kevin Andrew Spicer Originally made public by Project Gutenberg—taken from Project Gutenberg's version of the text. Prologue: ¶1 The story had held us, round the fire, sufficiently breathless, but except the obvious remark that it was gruesome, as, on Christmas Eve in an old house, a strange tale should essentially be, I remember no comment uttered till somebody happened to say that it was the only case he had met in which such a visitation had fallen on a child.</description></item><item><title>More _Turn of the Screw_ HTML Testing</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-more-tots-hmtl-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-more-tots-hmtl-testing/</guid><description>All right, so let&amp;rsquo;s do a little bit of testing of the whole XML through XSLT process to get an HTML version of James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw with all my colored tags for it.
The original .xml and .xsl file are up and available in the GitHub repo.
And without further ado, here we go!</description></item><item><title>Text Encoding Initiative (TEI) Fun with Henry James's _The Turn of the Screw_</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james/</guid><description>My English Department colleague, Dr. Anna Ioanes, is teaching the standard course in &amp;ldquo;Critical Theory&amp;rdquo; this semester and students have been working their way through Henry James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw over the last few weeks. Somehow—not exactly sure how—I managed to forget how incredibly rich this text is and this is not even to mention the rich secondary criticism produced by this short little novella. Inspired—once again—by some posts from Jonathan Reeve over at Columbia (specifically, his nice write-up about sentence lengths in James along with his encoded .</description></item><item><title>Binary Text Classification Fun! ... with some Literary Texts by Willa Cather and Sarah Orne Jewett</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts/</guid><description>In my DH journey, the work of Dr. William Mattingly has been something of a constant companion and guide.
His video laying out the steps for a &amp;ldquo;Binary Data Classification&amp;rdquo; was clear and quite clarifying for me in all kinds of ways. The classifier&amp;rsquo;s job in this video was to see if it could tell the difference between the work of Oscar Wilde and Dan Brown. What if we tried a different pair of authors/texts?</description></item></channel></rss>