<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XML on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/xml/</link><description>Recent content in XML on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/xml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visualizing Online Class Discussion Boards (_redux_)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</guid><description>In a very early post on this blog, I went through some of my incredibly kludgy attempts to visualize the discussion boards in my ENGL200: Introduction to Literature: Weird Fiction course that I have been teaching every semester since Fall of 2019. I have improved things quite a bit and made the worfklow a whole lot easier. I figured I could, once again, take everyone through the steps to see if it might be at all helpful for others with similar use-cases.</description></item><item><title>Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and you do a lot of teaching online (I know, I know, who among us don&amp;rsquo;t fit into that category today?) with courses that are really &amp;ldquo;Discussion Board&amp;rdquo;-heavy, you know that responding to students through Canvas&amp;rsquo;s LMS is, on its face, a bit of a bear. I have a tendency to produce some rather extensive comments to student posts each and every week. As Canvas veterans know all too well, there are all kinds of things about Canvas that are frighteningly &amp;ldquo;user-hostile,&amp;rdquo; as Robby Burns puts it.</description></item><item><title>Using Vector Space Models with Shakespeare's Plays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</guid><description>Much of the toe-dipping into this new DH field I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing as of late has centered around learning many of the kinds of projects carried out and then turning the methods within those projects onto mew artifacts. A while back I worked my way through Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont, and Allen Riddell&amp;rsquo;s Humanities Data Analysis: Case Studies with Python. I found a great deal of it thought-provoking and fascinating—especially the chapters devoted to modeling texts with vector spaces and the later chapter on stylometry, which focused on some texts by Hildegard of Bingen and Bernard of Clairvaux.</description></item></channel></rss>