<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pandas on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/pandas/</link><description>Recent content in pandas on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/pandas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let's Do Some Real World HTML Table Parsing with Beautiful Soup!</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-25-real-world-beautiful-soup-html-table-parsing/</guid><description>Given that I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to chronicle my DH journeys here, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d showcase a little bit of my utilization of scraping data from a website with Beautiful Soup (docs are here).
Doing some research for a favorite student of mine, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wandering around websites devoted to law school. One website here has a really fantastic little table on the page that has everything one could want—especially if one is a little behind on deadlines and trying to catch up a bit (i.</description></item><item><title>Using Vector Space Models with Shakespeare's Plays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare/</guid><description>Much of the toe-dipping into this new DH field I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing as of late has centered around learning many of the kinds of projects carried out and then turning the methods within those projects onto mew artifacts. A while back I worked my way through Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont, and Allen Riddell&amp;rsquo;s Humanities Data Analysis: Case Studies with Python. I found a great deal of it thought-provoking and fascinating—especially the chapters devoted to modeling texts with vector spaces and the later chapter on stylometry, which focused on some texts by Hildegard of Bingen and Bernard of Clairvaux.</description></item><item><title>Viral Tweet Classification Project</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project/</guid><description>I had a bit of fun recently working on a machine learning classification project using some Twitter data (said project coming through Codecademy). The goal was to see if we could write some code to properly detect whether or not a tweet was viral (using the K-Nearest Neighbors algorithm). I also played around with a logistic regression model as well. All the code for the following is available in this repo.</description></item><item><title>Letting Excel Go and Departmental Assessment Reports</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 08:19:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</guid><description>For those that work in disciplines that are much closer to STEM fields than me over here in philosophy and literature, I have no doubt that most of what I want to showcase here will no doubt be the height of banality. As Department Chair, a good deal of the Assessment Reports each year fall to me. Historically, for the past couple of years I have been more than content to simply just keep all of the scores on our assessed outcomes in one gigantic Excel spreadsheet.</description></item></channel></rss>