<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/api/</link><description>Recent content in API on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recent Canvas Changes to Threaded Discussion Board Posts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-09-01-recent-canvas-changes-to-discussions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:21:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-09-01-recent-canvas-changes-to-discussions/</guid><description>Introductory Remarks Recently, the Canvas LMS put through a change that no doubt will affect many of us. I received the following from my current institution&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Canvas Liason&amp;rdquo;:
Hello Faculty,
On August 14th, Canvas did an update to the new design for Discussions. In &amp;gt;the old design, you had the option for a threaded discussion. In the new &amp;gt;design, it was not there. When Canvas did the update, they set the ‘Disallow &amp;gt;threaded replies’ to on (checked).</description></item><item><title>What Kind of Songs Do I Like? Goofing Around with the Spotify API and My Bizarre Music Tastes</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</guid><description>Some Introductory Remarks I was having a conversation with my most favorite student that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had in my entire career as a teacher a while back and we got to chatting about my little pattern of sending her songs I like from the &amp;ldquo;Discover Weekly&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Release Radar&amp;rdquo; playlists that come my way via Spotify. She and I seem to have very few similarities when it comes to music. She likes to say that I have somewhat &amp;ldquo;girlish&amp;rdquo; music tastes (not meant as a pejorative, far from it, at least, I think!</description></item><item><title>More Python Fiddlework</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-09-21-more_python_fiddlework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-09-21-more_python_fiddlework/</guid><description>Recently I came across a wonderful YouTube Channel, Arjan Codes, and I have already learned a great deal from many of his videos, tutorials, etc. (In particular, I found his video on the use of type hinting in Python to be incredibly helpful, and I have already started to implement some of his suggestions in my own code.) Wanting to just try it out I figured I would put a pretty simple snippet of code that is part of my ever-continuing enjoyment of working with our Canvas LMS solely through the API—trying never to open a web browser.</description></item></channel></rss>