<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NBA on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/nba/</link><description>Recent content in NBA on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:03:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/nba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Even More NBA Stats: Top Ten All-Time Scorers' Scoring Trajectories Over Their Careers</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-12-top_ten_scoring_leaders_scoring_trajectories/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:03:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-12-top_ten_scoring_leaders_scoring_trajectories/</guid><description>Given my last two posts on Klay Thompson and LeBron James’ PPG over their careers, I go to thinking about the top 10 scoring leaders all time (Kevin Durant recently moved up the list](https://www.bbc.com/sport/basketball/articles/cvgrqe2eggjo) past Wilt Chamberlain). How about plotting their stats all together? Let’s do it (all the code in R to reproduce these is available here in the &amp;ldquo;scripts&amp;rdquo; folder)! I have a number of different visualizations so go have a look-see!</description></item><item><title>Even More NBA Stats ... but in R no less!: LeBron James's Career PPG (and maybe MJ too)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-11-nba_stats_in_r_lebron_james/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:01:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-11-nba_stats_in_r_lebron_james/</guid><description>A couple of days ago (January 9, 2026) I watched LeBron and the Lakers take on the Milwaukee Bucks. He played well (26, 9, and 10 is pretty damned good, in fact.) Figures I would use the code from my previous post on Klay Thompson. Here’s what we get (including the more generalized code I promised).
The more generalized code I promised first:
# Install packages (only need to do this once) install.</description></item><item><title>More NBA Stats ... but in R no less!: Klay Thompson's Career PPG</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-10-nba_stats_in_r_klay_thompson/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:01:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2026-01-10-nba_stats_in_r_klay_thompson/</guid><description>On Thursday, January 8th I was watching the Dallas Mavericks play the Utah Jazz. Early on Klay Thompson seemed a little off. I thought of his time back in Golden State (I was actually in San Francisco in 2015 when the Warriors won the title) and thought about how far we have all fallen (this was a little premature, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, as he finished 23, 3, and 5, IIRC). I got it into my head to see what the stats say.</description></item><item><title>NBA Regular Season Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</guid><description>So, spending some time looking at NBA blouwouts in the playoffs over time in previous posts, I wondered about blowouts in the regular season.
I found a dataset on Kaggle Datasets that had data from the very start of the NBA up until today.
So, we filtered out all the regular season games and then plotted the data. We have the raw blowout data in the first image and then the proportions in the second plot below:</description></item></channel></rss>