<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Economic Analyses: High-Yield Savings Accounts (HYSA) and Bitcoin ... Given Posible Reduction in the Interest Rate by the FED</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</guid><description>Okay, so recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving into using my Python knowledge to look at and analyze financial data. We know that the FED is next scheduled to meet on December 17-18 of this year. Many are predicting that we will see a decrease in interest rates.
So, if you have your money in a High-Yield Savings Account (HYSA)&amp;mdash;which you obviously should&amp;mdash;would it make more sense to move it elsewhere &amp;hellip; say, into Crypto?</description></item><item><title>Recent Canvas Changes to Threaded Discussion Board Posts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-29-recent-canvas-changes-to-discussions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:21:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-29-recent-canvas-changes-to-discussions/</guid><description>Introductory Remarks Recently, the Canvas LMS put through a change that no doubt will affect many of us. I received the following from my current institution&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Canvas Liason&amp;rdquo;:
Hello Faculty,
On August 14th, Canvas did an update to the new design for Discussions. In &amp;gt;the old design, you had the option for a threaded discussion. In the new &amp;gt;design, it was not there. When Canvas did the update, they set the ‘Disallow &amp;gt;threaded replies’ to on (checked).</description></item><item><title>Total *non sequitur*: Tracking the Price of Silver</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-30-tracking-silver-prices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-08-30-tracking-silver-prices/</guid><description>Silver Price Tracker So, my father has some vintage Silver pieces from 1973 and 1974 produced by the Franklin Mint with all kinds of different national banks on each one. We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to figure out how to unload them&amp;mdash;either to collectors or to folks that will simply melt them down for the silver alone. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a little coding.
The first is a plot over the last couple of months of Silver prices:</description></item><item><title>What Kind of Songs Do I Like? Goofing Around with the Spotify API and My Bizarre Music Tastes</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-what-kind-of-songs-do-i-like/</guid><description>Some Introductory Remarks I was having a conversation with my most favorite student that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had in my entire career as a teacher a while back and we got to chatting about my little pattern of sending her songs I like from the &amp;ldquo;Discover Weekly&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Release Radar&amp;rdquo; playlists that come my way via Spotify. She and I seem to have very few similarities when it comes to music. She likes to say that I have somewhat &amp;ldquo;girlish&amp;rdquo; music tastes (not meant as a pejorative, far from it, at least, I think!</description></item><item><title>Digital Rhetoric and Predictive Machine Learning Models on Twitter Data</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-measuring-twitter-engagement-and-digital-rhetoric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-measuring-twitter-engagement-and-digital-rhetoric/</guid><description>In my ENGE 515: Digital Rhetoric graduate-level course currently running (full list of courses is available through the USF REAL program, housed within the College of Education), we have been getting our feet wet in this field of rhetoric focused on the realm/world of &amp;ldquo;the digital&amp;rdquo; (I do notice too now—somehow it had slipped my mind—that I wrote a little bit already about how this course went last summer). This past week (Week 6), we had a read of some somewhat contemporary work in this field, namely:</description></item><item><title>More Python Fiddlework</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-09-21-more_python_fiddlework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-09-21-more_python_fiddlework/</guid><description>Recently I came across a wonderful YouTube Channel, Arjan Codes, and I have already learned a great deal from many of his videos, tutorials, etc. (In particular, I found his video on the use of type hinting in Python to be incredibly helpful, and I have already started to implement some of his suggestions in my own code.) Wanting to just try it out I figured I would put a pretty simple snippet of code that is part of my ever-continuing enjoyment of working with our Canvas LMS solely through the API—trying never to open a web browser.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Logging in Python</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-advanced-logging-in-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-25-advanced-logging-in-python/</guid><description>Over this past weekend I was working my through Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Advanced Python 3&amp;rdquo; course, which has an initial module that introduces students to Python&amp;rsquo;s logging library. There was a wonderful little project—&amp;ldquo;ATM Logging&amp;rdquo;—that was quite fun to tackle, especially as it made really clear why one might want to use logging instead of filling one&amp;rsquo;s code with a bunch of print() statements. The setup was that we had a pretty simple little &amp;ldquo;ATM&amp;rdquo; program/script that would allow us to deposit and withdraw money—while providing some error messages to keep track of things throughout the whole process.</description></item><item><title>Predictive Modeling with the 'OK Cupid' Dataset</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-machine-learning-with-ok-cupid-dataset/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-machine-learning-with-ok-cupid-dataset/</guid><description>The final project for Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Building a Machine Learning Model with Python&amp;rdquo; Skill Path asks students to do a little work with the &amp;ldquo;OK Cupid&amp;rdquo; dataset—the project is humorously, punningly titled: &amp;ldquo;Date-A-Scientist.&amp;rdquo; Students were tasked with trying to build some models to make predictions on this dataset. A Jupyter notebook with all the code and results follows here:</description></item><item><title>Hemingway (continued)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-fitzgerald-hemingway-continued/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-15-fitzgerald-hemingway-continued/</guid><description>In my last post, I shared some really simple text classification work on Hemingway, Fitzgerald, and Steinbeck. It was only after posting it that I noticed that Justin Rice beat me to the punch with his post &amp;ldquo;What Makes Hemingway Hemingway?&amp;rdquo; over on &amp;ldquo;The LitCharts Blog&amp;rdquo;. What was terribly curious to me was that Rice showcases some of the key characteristics that one thinks &amp;ldquo;makes Hemingway Hemingway&amp;rdquo;—sentence length, word length, lexical richness, dialogue proportion, parts of speech, characteristic words, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Fitzgerald ... Hemingway ... Steinbeck</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-07-fitzgerald-hemingway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-04-07-fitzgerald-hemingway/</guid><description>Lately I have been spending a fair amount of time working on my portfolio for the required &amp;ldquo;Post_Tenure Review&amp;rdquo; at my current institution. I spent quite a bit of time canvassing a great deal of the DH/computer programming learning I have acquired over the last couple of years. I gave a somewhat interesting test project version of some more stylometry/text classification work,1 focusing quite directly on some work another (former) student of mine, William Mastin, and I have been doing on one of his most favorite authors, Ernest Hemingway.</description></item><item><title>Interacting with the Canvas Live API</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-canvas-live-api-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-canvas-live-api-work/</guid><description>In a previous post (&amp;ldquo;Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback&amp;rdquo;), I recounted some of the ways I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the CanvasAPI python library from ucfopen to help with responding to discussion board posts from students each week. I have had a couple of times when running the script shown in that post where something goes slightly awry: perhaps I have mistyped one of the student or assignment ids and the script runs into an error while iterating through the dataframe that contains all of the data I want to upload.</description></item><item><title>Network Graph Visualization with Bokeh (Testing)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-02-05-network-visualization-with-bokeh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-02-05-network-visualization-with-bokeh/</guid><description>Just testing the interactive bokeh plot here:
Again, all help for this goes to Barry Sunderland over here.</description></item><item><title>Automating Syllabus Updating</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-syllabus-maker-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-syllabus-maker-stuff/</guid><description>In my previous post I mentioned off-handedly the task of updating the dates on my syllabi as I transition from the Fall to the Spring to the Summer semesters. I figured I would post some of the code to help out with this tiny little mini-project. (All the code for this is available in the following repository.)
I have a pretty simple Canvas main page that has all the dates, readings, and assignments laid out in a simple little table—all on one main page:</description></item><item><title>Playing around with ChatGPT</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-playing-around-with-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-12-19-playing-around-with-chatgpt/</guid><description>So, like so many (here and here as nice and simple examples—heck, even Graham Harman has gotten into the discussion here) in the computer science field, I have been playing around with the newly-released &amp;ldquo;ChatGPT&amp;rdquo; chatbot released through openAI. It&amp;rsquo;s also that time of the year when we academics start turning to getting all of those syllabi for the upcoming Spring semester ready to go. We all now how onerous it can be to create, say, a reading schedule with dates that we always need to shift when we move from one semester to another.</description></item><item><title>Training a SpaCy Text Classifier on Supreme Court Opinions: Classifying Opinions by Century</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-09-20-classifying-supreme-court-cases-by-century-with-spacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-09-20-classifying-supreme-court-cases-by-century-with-spacy/</guid><description>Continuing some work with the Supreme Court databases I&amp;rsquo;ve been fiddling around with lately, I was wondering if I could get a machine learning model to be able to correctly identify and classify a Supreme Court opinion by the decade in which it was written. So let&amp;rsquo;s grab some data and see what we can do!
There is a really wonderful github repo that contains the .json files of all the Supreme Court cases made available through the CourtListener API.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Online Class Discussion Boards (redux)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</guid><description>In a very early post on this blog, I went through some of my incredibly kludgy attempts to visualize the discussion boards in my ENGL200: Introduction to Literature: Weird Fiction course that I have been teaching every semester since Fall of 2019. I have improved things quite a bit and made the worfklow a whole lot easier. I figured I could, once again, take everyone through the steps to see if it might be at all helpful for others with similar use-cases.</description></item><item><title>Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and you do a lot of teaching online (I know, I know, who among us don&amp;rsquo;t fit into that category today?) with courses that are really &amp;ldquo;Discussion Board&amp;rdquo;-heavy, you know that responding to students through Canvas&amp;rsquo;s LMS is, on its face, a bit of a bear. I have a tendency to produce some rather extensive comments to student posts each and every week. As Canvas veterans know all too well, there are all kinds of things about Canvas that are frighteningly &amp;ldquo;user-hostile,&amp;rdquo; as Robby Burns puts it.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Stylistic Tendencies of Recent United States Supreme Court Justices (Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</guid><description>General Introduction (All of the code for this post is available in this repo here.)
Continuing off of the last two posts (here and here), I thought we might continue seeing what we could do with our Supreme Court Opinions dataset(s)—I was also fascinated and inspired by a nice little article on Wikipedia about the &amp;ldquo;Ideological leanings of United States Supreme Court justices,&amp;rdquo; which has some really nice images. I thought one might do a little exploratory work with the opinions of some of the more recently appointed Justices: in particular I wanted to look at the work done so far by Justices Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett; perhaps a little PCA work to see if we could work through any potential stylistic similarities between their opinions so far.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Utilizing the Top2Vec Library</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_20/</guid><description>Here in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue working on the same project used in the previous post (here) while trying out the Top2Vec library). As is so often the case, I came across this library via Dr. William Mattingly&amp;rsquo;s YoutTube channel, who devoted two different videos to using this library (here and here). So let&amp;rsquo;s jump in and see what we can do with this library.
This time around we&amp;rsquo;re using a slightly different dataset that comes Kaggle—it contains all of the USSC opinions from 1970 on.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Surrounding Abortion</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</guid><description>General Background (All code from this section is available in this repository here.)
Friday of last week, June 24th, 2022, was a profoundly dark day for a great many of us in the United States. Feeling somewhat helpless as the Supreme Court published the final draft of Dobbs v. Jackson Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Organization, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but fall back on old patterns. Not really knowing what else to do—I had a student with whom I had recently read the leaked original draft posted by Politico—I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but say to her when the opinion came down that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what else to do other than to get to reading.</description></item><item><title>Linear Regression in the Humanities(?!?!) ... not quite</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities_18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities_18/</guid><description>Working my way through some of the new lessons from Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;Data Scientist: Natural Language Processing Specialist&amp;rdquo; path, I was returning to some of the lessons on linear regression usage in machine learning contexts. I also happened across a really fantastic post from the &amp;ldquo;LaTeX Ninja&amp;rdquo; on &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning for the Humanities: A Very Short Introduction&amp;rdquo;—I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet come across this site yet and find it full of all kinds of fantastic little nuggets.</description></item><item><title>Fetching Data from a TOML File into a HUGO Table</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table_17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table_17/</guid><description>Continuing to learn the whole HUGO ecosystem here, I figured I would try a little testing of some things. What if I had a bunch of data in a simple .json or .toml or .yaml or whatever file and wanted to pull/fetch data from that file into one of my posts? I did have some data from the last post about Henry James&amp;rsquo;s use of certain words that we used to generate some of the graphs.</description></item><item><title>More _The Turn of the Screw_ Data Analysis</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis_16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis_16/</guid><description>I know I mentioned in an earlier post—and here—that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of work with Henry James&amp;rsquo;s canonical The Turn of the Screw. I thought I would post a little bit more here of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to as of late with this. A student of mine was fascinated by the use of the words &amp;ldquo;prodigious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;portentous&amp;rdquo; in the Governess&amp;rsquo;s narrative in Turn. She said she noticed it frequently.</description></item><item><title>Turn of the Screw TEI-Encoded (pure HTML)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-hj_tots_full_version_13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-16-hj_tots_full_version_13/</guid><description>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> &lt;!DOCTYPE html> &lt;italic>The Turn of the Screw The Turn of the Screw By Henry James Encoded by: &amp;nbsp;Dr. Kevin Andrew Spicer Originally made public by Project Gutenberg—taken from their version of the text. Prologue: ¶1 The story had held us, round the fire, sufficiently breathless, but except the obvious remark that it was gruesome, as, on Christmas Eve in an old house, a strange tale should essentially be, I remember no comment uttered till somebody happened to say that it was the only case he had met in which such a visitation had fallen on a child.</description></item><item><title>Transforming TEI XML of _The Turn of the Screw_ into HTML</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-15-more-tots-hmtl-testing_introductory_post_12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-15-more-tots-hmtl-testing_introductory_post_12/</guid><description>All right, so let&amp;rsquo;s do a little bit of testing of the whole XML through XSLT process to get an HTML version of James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw with all my colored tags for it.
The original .xml and .xsl file are up and available in the GitHub repo.
And without further ado, here we go!</description></item><item><title>Text Encoding Initiative (TEI) Fun with Henry James's _The Turn of the Screw_</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james_11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-20-tei-encoding-with-henry-james_11/</guid><description>My English Department colleague, Dr. Anna Ioanes, is teaching the standard course in &amp;ldquo;Critical Theory&amp;rdquo; this semester and students have been working their way through Henry James&amp;rsquo;s The Turn of the Screw over the last few weeks. Somehow—not exactly sure how—I managed to forget how incredibly rich this text is and this is not even to mention the rich secondary criticism produced by this short little novella. Inspired—once again—by some posts from Jonathan Reeve over at Columbia (specifically, his nice write-up about sentence lengths in James along with his encoded .</description></item><item><title>Binary Text Classification Fun! ... with some Literary Texts by Willa Cather and Sarah Orne Jewett</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts_10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts_10/</guid><description>In my DH journey, the work of Dr. William Mattingly has been something of a constant companion and guide.
His video laying out the steps for a &amp;ldquo;Binary Data Classification&amp;rdquo; was clear and quite clarifying for me in all kinds of ways. The classifier&amp;rsquo;s job in this video was to see if it could tell the difference between the work of Oscar Wilde and Dan Brown. What if we tried a different pair of authors/texts?</description></item><item><title>Using Vector Space Models with Shakespeare's Plays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</guid><description>Much of the toe-dipping into this new DH field I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing as of late has centered around learning many of the kinds of projects carried out and then turning the methods within those projects onto mew artifacts. A while back I worked my way through Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont, and Allen Riddell&amp;rsquo;s Humanities Data Analysis: Case Studies with Python. I found a great deal of it thought-provoking and fascinating—especially the chapters devoted to modeling texts with vector spaces and the later chapter on stylometry, which focused on some texts by Hildegard of Bingen and Bernard of Clairvaux.</description></item><item><title>Viral Tweet Classification Project</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project_08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project_08/</guid><description>I had a bit of fun recently working on a machine learning classification project using some Twitter data (said project coming through Codecademy). The goal was to see if we could write some code to properly detect whether or not a tweet was viral (using the K-Nearest Neighbors algorithm). I also played around with a logistic regression model as well. All the code for the following is available in this repo.</description></item><item><title>Sentiment Analysis of Some Chicagoland Universities' Main Twitter Accounts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-02-15-twitter-sentiment-analysis_07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-02-15-twitter-sentiment-analysis_07/</guid><description>Well, February has come around and that&amp;rsquo;s the time at my school where we get all kinds of nice financial data about how wages and compensation by faculty rank compare between a number of &amp;ldquo;peer institutions&amp;rdquo; (the usual ones linked with USF here in Chicagoland are Benedictine, Dominican, Lewis, and Saint Xavier) I wondered a bit if one might do a little bit of data visualization not of financial information, but of, say, Twitter accounts.</description></item><item><title>Letting Excel Go and Departmental Assessment Reports</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 08:19:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-01-18-letting-excel-go_06/</guid><description>For those that work in disciplines that are much closer to STEM fields than me over here in philosophy and literature, I have no doubt that most of what I want to showcase here will no doubt be the height of banality. As Department Chair, a good deal of the Assessment Reports each year fall to me. Historically, for the past couple of years I have been more than content to simply just keep all of the scores on our assessed outcomes in one gigantic Excel spreadsheet.</description></item></channel></rss>