<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sklearn on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/sklearn/</link><description>Recent content in sklearn on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/sklearn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comparing Stylistic Tendencies of Recent United States Supreme Court Justices (Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-11-pca-analysis-of-recent-new-justices_21/</guid><description>General Introduction (All of the code for this post is available in this repo here.)
Continuing off of the last two posts (here and here), I thought we might continue seeing what we could do with our Supreme Court Opinions dataset(s)—I was also fascinated and inspired by a nice little article on Wikipedia about the &amp;ldquo;Ideological leanings of United States Supreme Court justices,&amp;rdquo; which has some really nice images. I thought one might do a little exploratory work with the opinions of some of the more recently appointed Justices: in particular I wanted to look at the work done so far by Justices Gorsuch, Kavanaugh, and Barrett; perhaps a little PCA work to see if we could work through any potential stylistic similarities between their opinions so far.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Surrounding Abortion</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_19/</guid><description>General Background (All code from this section is available in this repository here.)
Friday of last week, June 24th, 2022, was a profoundly dark day for a great many of us in the United States. Feeling somewhat helpless as the Supreme Court published the final draft of Dobbs v. Jackson Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Organization, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but fall back on old patterns. Not really knowing what else to do—I had a student with whom I had recently read the leaked original draft posted by Politico—I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but say to her when the opinion came down that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what else to do other than to get to reading.</description></item><item><title>Binary Text Classification Fun! ... with some Literary Texts by Willa Cather and Sarah Orne Jewett</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts_10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-04-10-classification-fun-with-some-literary-texts_10/</guid><description>In my DH journey, the work of Dr. William Mattingly has been something of a constant companion and guide.
His video laying out the steps for a &amp;ldquo;Binary Data Classification&amp;rdquo; was clear and quite clarifying for me in all kinds of ways. The classifier&amp;rsquo;s job in this video was to see if it could tell the difference between the work of Oscar Wilde and Dan Brown. What if we tried a different pair of authors/texts?</description></item><item><title>Using Vector Space Models with Shakespeare's Plays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-29-vector-space-models-and-shakespeare_09/</guid><description>Much of the toe-dipping into this new DH field I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing as of late has centered around learning many of the kinds of projects carried out and then turning the methods within those projects onto mew artifacts. A while back I worked my way through Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont, and Allen Riddell&amp;rsquo;s Humanities Data Analysis: Case Studies with Python. I found a great deal of it thought-provoking and fascinating—especially the chapters devoted to modeling texts with vector spaces and the later chapter on stylometry, which focused on some texts by Hildegard of Bingen and Bernard of Clairvaux.</description></item><item><title>Viral Tweet Classification Project</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project_08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-03-26-twitter-viral-tweet-classification-project_08/</guid><description>I had a bit of fun recently working on a machine learning classification project using some Twitter data (said project coming through Codecademy). The goal was to see if we could write some code to properly detect whether or not a tweet was viral (using the K-Nearest Neighbors algorithm). I also played around with a logistic regression model as well. All the code for the following is available in this repo.</description></item></channel></rss>