<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>json on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/json/</link><description>Recent content in json on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/json/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WNBA Regular Season Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-07-06-wnba-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-07-06-wnba-blowouts/</guid><description>Given that we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work with the NBA and &amp;ldquo;blowouts&amp;rdquo; in a couple of different posts&amp;mdash;one here and another here&amp;mdash;I thought we might look at the WNBA too. So, first step, I found a Kaggle dataset that gave us data up until 2020, if I remember correctly. We then wrote some code to update to the most latest games:
import pandas as pd import numpy as np from nba_api.</description></item><item><title>NBA Regular Season Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-24-nba-regular-season-blowouts/</guid><description>So, spending some time looking at NBA blouwouts in the playoffs over time in previous posts, I wondered about blowouts in the regular season.
I found a dataset on Kaggle Datasets that had data from the very start of the NBA up until today.
So, we filtered out all the regular season games and then plotted the data. We have the raw blowout data in the first image and then the proportions in the second plot below:</description></item><item><title>As Promised---Skubal and Skenes Career K Projections</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-19-skubal_vs_skenes/</guid><description>As in my previous post I promised to look at both Skenes and Skubal and their projected trajectories towards 3000 career strikeouts. If we&amp;rsquo;re being honest, this benchmark is far from easy to achieve, only 19 pitchers in the history of baseball have done it before:
Pitcher Strikeouts Nolan Ryan 5,714 Randy Johnson 4,875 Roger Clemens 4,672 Steve Carlton 4,136 Bert Blyleven 3,701 Tom Seaver 3,640 Don Sutton 3,574 Gaylord Perry 3,534 Walter Johnson 3,509 Greg Maddux 3,371 Phil Niekro 3,342 Ferguson Jenkins 3,192 Pedro Martinez 3,154 Bob Gibson 3,117 Curt Schilling 3,116 CC Sabathia 3,093 John Smoltz 3,084 Justin Verlander 3,041 Max Scherzer 3,000 (IIRC, CC Sabathia and Justin Verlander are also on this list too.</description></item><item><title>More MLB Visualizations ... For a Larf</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-17-skubal-k-projections/</guid><description>With Tarik Skubal on the mound tomorrow&amp;mdash;Wednesday, June 18&amp;mdash;for the Tigers against Pittsburgh, considered by many to be the best pitcher in baseball, I thought we could take a look at Skubal&amp;rsquo;s projections real quick as a larf. I figured we could use the code from our previous blog post looking at Paul Skenes and Clayton Kershaw and see what we can see; just a couple changes to the player we&amp;rsquo;re looking at and we’re good to go:</description></item><item><title>We've Done Some NBA and WNBA Data Analysis ... How About Some MLB?</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-15-skenes-vs-kershaw-career-strikeouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-06-15-skenes-vs-kershaw-career-strikeouts/</guid><description>Watching the LA Dodgers and SF Giants game yesterday&amp;mdash;Saturday, June 14, 2025&amp;mdash;the commentators were talking about Clayton Kershaw&amp;rsquo;s closing in a on 3000 career strikeouts. Having earlier watched Pittsburgh Pirates ace Paul Skenes go, I wonder if we could visualize the possibilities of the latter eventually clearing that line.
We can project Paul Skenes&amp;rsquo;s trajectory based on some estimates&amp;mdash;whether we&amp;rsquo;re really optimistic in certain K numbers per game or pessimistic&amp;mdash;and we get something like this:</description></item><item><title>WNBA Historical Stats</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-wnba-historical-stats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-wnba-historical-stats/</guid><description>Yay! The WNBA season is upon us and already started! Since I had recently done some analysis on the NBA Playoffs&amp;mdash;I figured I would goof around and play with the WNBA a little bit. In service of that, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
So, as always, we start with data gathering. I tried using the fabulous nba_api to grab data, but for years closer to the creation of the league (1997), things seemed a little spotty to me.</description></item><item><title>NBA Playoff Blowouts</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-nba-playoff-blowouts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 13:01:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-05-24-nba-playoff-blowouts/</guid><description>Watching the 2025 NBA Playoffs has been a bit strange: huge blowouts (sometimes, often, unexpected) follow by razor-tight contests that go down to the very last possession or even into overtime.
After the Denver Nuggets&amp;rsquo; exit from the playoffs at the hands of the OKC Thunder, Aaron Gordon of the Nuggets has a rather intriguing post-game press conference where he himself mentioned the &amp;ldquo;blowouts&amp;rdquo; thing (thus making it not something just in my head, I suppose).</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin vs. the DOW and NASDAQ</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-01-06-cryptos-vs-dow-jones-and-nasdaq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2025-01-06-cryptos-vs-dow-jones-and-nasdaq/</guid><description>So there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk lately about Microstrategy&amp;rsquo;s seemingly almost constant buys of Bitcoin almost every single day. There&amp;rsquo;s also been quite a lot of chatter recently about some other hardware companies, (Marvel Technologies, MARA, etc.) getting involved. We also have things like &amp;ldquo;Coinbase&amp;rdquo; that is frequently linked to Bitcoin as well.
I thought I would do some coding to see how correlated these stock tickers are with Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Building a Dash App to Visualize the 5, 13, 8 EMA Investment Strategy</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-14-building_a_dash_app_to_visualize_investment_strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-14-building_a_dash_app_to_visualize_investment_strategy/</guid><description>So, continuing to goof-around a little bit with applying my Python knowledge to analysis of the stock markets, I decided to build a Dash app with Plotly that would allow one to see real-time price action while also implementing the well-known &amp;ldquo;5-13-8 EMA&amp;rdquo; trading strategy.
It&amp;rsquo;s still a work-in-progress to be sure &amp;hellip; and it&amp;rsquo;s probably totally unnecessary&amp;mdash;such indicators and plots are quickly and easily used on platforms like Trading View and Ninja Trader, but I wondered if I could do myself, from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Economic Analyses: High-Yield Savings Accounts (HYSA) and Bitcoin ... Given Posible Reduction in the Interest Rate by the FED</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2024-12-12-hysa-versus-bitcoin/</guid><description>Okay, so recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving into using my Python knowledge to look at and analyze financial data. We know that the FED is next scheduled to meet on December 17-18 of this year. Many are predicting that we will see a decrease in interest rates.
So, if you have your money in a High-Yield Savings Account (HYSA)&amp;mdash;which you obviously should&amp;mdash;would it make more sense to move it elsewhere &amp;hellip; say, into Crypto?</description></item><item><title>Interacting with the Canvas Live API</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-canvas-live-api-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-canvas-live-api-work/</guid><description>In a previous post (&amp;ldquo;Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback&amp;rdquo;), I recounted some of the ways I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the CanvasAPI python library from ucfopen to help with responding to discussion board posts from students each week. I have had a couple of times when running the script shown in that post where something goes slightly awry: perhaps I have mistyped one of the student or assignment ids and the script runs into an error while iterating through the dataframe that contains all of the data I want to upload.</description></item><item><title>Network Graph Visualization with Bokeh (Testing)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-02-05-network-visualization-with-bokeh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2023-02-05-network-visualization-with-bokeh/</guid><description>Just testing the interactive bokeh plot here:
Again, all help for this goes to Barry Sunderland over here.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Online Class Discussion Boards (redux)</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-20-visualizing-discussion-boards-redux_23/</guid><description>In a very early post on this blog, I went through some of my incredibly kludgy attempts to visualize the discussion boards in my ENGL200: Introduction to Literature: Weird Fiction course that I have been teaching every semester since Fall of 2019. I have improved things quite a bit and made the worfklow a whole lot easier. I figured I could, once again, take everyone through the steps to see if it might be at all helpful for others with similar use-cases.</description></item><item><title>Automating Canvas Discussion Board Grading and Feedback</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-15-automating-canvas-grading-and-feedback_22/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and you do a lot of teaching online (I know, I know, who among us don&amp;rsquo;t fit into that category today?) with courses that are really &amp;ldquo;Discussion Board&amp;rdquo;-heavy, you know that responding to students through Canvas&amp;rsquo;s LMS is, on its face, a bit of a bear. I have a tendency to produce some rather extensive comments to student posts each and every week. As Canvas veterans know all too well, there are all kinds of things about Canvas that are frighteningly &amp;ldquo;user-hostile,&amp;rdquo; as Robby Burns puts it.</description></item></channel></rss>