<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python for digital humanities on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/python-for-digital-humanities/</link><description>Recent content in python for digital humanities on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/python-for-digital-humanities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Utilizing the Top2Vec Library</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-blank-top2vec-topic-modeling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-blank-top2vec-topic-modeling/</guid><description>Here in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue working on the same project used in the previous post (here) while trying out the Top2Vec library). As is so often the case, I came across this library via Dr. William Mattingly&amp;rsquo;s YoutTube channel, who devoted two different videos to using this library (here and here). So let&amp;rsquo;s jump in and see what we can do with this library.
This time around we&amp;rsquo;re using a slightly different dataset that comes Kaggle—it contains all of the USSC opinions from 1970 on.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Surrounding Abortion</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc/</guid><description>General Background (All code from this section is available in this repository here.)
Friday of last week, June 24th, 2022, was a profoundly dark day for a great many of us in the United States. Feeling somewhat helpless as the Supreme Court published the final draft of Dobbs v. Jackson Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Organization, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but fall back on old patterns. Not really knowing what else to do—I had a student with whom I had recently read the leaked original draft posted by Politico—I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but say to her when the opinion came down that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what else to do other than to get to reading.</description></item><item><title>Linear Regression in the Humanities(?!?!) ... not quite</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-06-01-linear-regression-in-the-humanities/</guid><description>Working my way through some of the new lessons from Codecademy&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;Data Scientist: Natural Language Processing Specialist&amp;rdquo; path, I was returning to some of the lessons on linear regression usage in machine learning contexts. I also happened across a really fantastic post from the &amp;ldquo;LaTeX Ninja&amp;rdquo; on &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning for the Humanities: A Very Short Introduction&amp;rdquo;—I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet come across this site yet and find it full of all kinds of fantastic little nuggets.</description></item><item><title>Fetching Data from a TOML File into a HUGO Table</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-29-toml-data-to-hugo-table/</guid><description>Continuing to learn the whole HUGO ecosystem here, I figured I would try a little testing of some things. What if I had a bunch of data in a simple .json or .toml or .yaml or whatever file and wanted to pull/fetch data from that file into one of my posts? I did have some data from the last post about Henry James&amp;rsquo;s use of certain words that we used to generate some of the graphs.</description></item><item><title>More _The Turn of the Screw_ Data Analysis</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-05-27-henry-james-turn-of-the-screw-data-analysis/</guid><description>I know I mentioned in an earlier post—a couple of different posts actually (here and here too)—that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of work with Henry James&amp;rsquo;s canonical The Turn of the Screw. I thought I would post a little bit more here of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to as of late with this. A student of mine was fascinated by the use of the words &amp;ldquo;prodigious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;portentous&amp;rdquo; in the Governess&amp;rsquo;s narrative in Turn.</description></item></channel></rss>