<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ussc on Digital Forays</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/ussc/</link><description>Recent content in ussc on Digital Forays</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kspicer80.github.io/tags/ussc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Utilizing the Top2Vec Library</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-top2vec-topic-modeling_21/</guid><description>Here in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue working on the same project used in the previous post (here) while trying out the Top2Vec library). As is so often the case, I came across this library via Dr. William Mattingly&amp;rsquo;s YoutTube channel, who devoted two different videos to using this library (here and here). So let&amp;rsquo;s jump in and see what we can do with this library.
This time around we&amp;rsquo;re using a slightly different dataset that comes Kaggle—it contains all of the USSC opinions from 1970 on.</description></item><item><title>Topic Modeling the United States Supreme Court Surrounding Abortion</title><link>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kspicer80.github.io/posts/2022-07-06-topic-modeling-the-ussc_20/</guid><description>General Background (All code from this section is available in this repository here.)
Friday of last week, June 24th, 2022, was a profoundly dark day for a great many of us in the United States. Feeling somewhat helpless as the Supreme Court published the final draft of Dobbs v. Jackson Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Organization, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but fall back on old patterns. Not really knowing what else to do—I had a student with whom I had recently read the leaked original draft posted by Politico—I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but say to her when the opinion came down that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what else to do other than to get to reading.</description></item></channel></rss>